Guide to the Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc. Records TAM.250
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Three Arrows Cooperative Society Records
1937-2016
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc.
Balgley, Halona W.
Heinrich, Amy Vladeck
TAM.250
14.25 Linear Feet in 12 record cartons, 4 manuscript boxes, and 2 oversize folders.
The Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc. is the successor organization to the Barger Street Cooperative Society, chartered in 1937. Early members purchased 125 acres of farmland in Putnam Valley, NY and formed a cooperative summer colony which eventually grew to include 75 individual units. The colony, sometimes known as Camp Three Arrows, is modeled on socialist and communitarian values and offers residents a wide range of cultural, educational and leisure activities. Records include minutes of the Board of Directors and other governing bodies, financial and legal documents, correspondence, and printed material on the history of the Society. The collection also includes over three hundred and fifty photographs and eleven maps of the property and surrounding areas.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Board of Director of the Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc. sent a gift of papers and photographs related to the Three Arrows in Summer 2001. Further accretions have been donated in 2011, 2014, 2015, and 2017. Amy Vladek Heinrich sent a gift of materials used in an exhibit for the 70th Anniversary of Three Arrows Cooperative Society, including photographs or photocopies of photographs (approximately 130), text, printed materials and graphics, and loose captions in 2011. Heinrich also sent a gift of newsletters and governance documents in 2014. In 2015, Halona W. Balgley donated a further accretion to the collection. The accession number associated with these gifts are 2001.189, 2001.191, NPA.2003.092, NPA.2004.063, 2011.133, 2011.140, 2014.153, 2015.068, and 2017.080. Amy Vladek Heinrich sent a gift of materials used in an exhibit for the 70th Anniversary of Three Arrows Cooperative Society, including photographs or photocopies of photographs (approximately 130), text, printed materials and graphics, and loose captions in 2011. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2011.140 and 2011.133. Heinrich also sent a gift of newsletters and governance documents in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.153. In 2015, Halona W. Balgley donated a further accretion to the collection; the accession number associated with this gift is 2015.068.
Arrangement
Organized into ten series:
Series I: Minutes, 1937-2002
Series II: General Files, 1937-2003
Series III: Unprocessed Materials, 1930s-2000s
Series IV: Addendum (2001)
Series V: Photographs, 1940-2006
Series VI: Maps and Plans, 1937-1981
Series VII. 2014 Addendum
Series VIII. Archived Website
Series IX: 2015 Addendum
Series X. 2017 Addendum
Series I is arranged alphabetically by body or committee, and chronologically within each; Series II and IV through VI are arranged alphabetically by topic. Series III, IX, and X are unprocessed.
Historical Note
The cooperative colony managed by Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc. originated with the purchase of Barger Farm, a hilly 125-acre property in Putnam Valley, NY in December 1936. The original organizers, among whom were Louis Hay, a psychologist, Joseph Glass, an attorney, and Jack Schaffer, a member of the Socialist Party familiar with the local area, obtained a state charter as the Barger Street Cooperative Society in 1937 and began to sell shares in the venture for $100, with a minimum purchase of two shares. By the end of the second season thirty families had purchased shares, and a number of tents had been erected on the property. Many of the first participants were affiliated with the International Ladies Garment Workers Union, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the Jewish Labor Bund, the Socialist Party, USA, or the Party's youth group, the Young People's Socialist League. Some had attended socialist summer camps as children. The colony later adopted the name Three Arrows Cooperative Society to honor a traditional symbol of the international socialist movement. An important influence on the early members was long-time Socialist Party leader, Norman Thomas, who visited Three Arrows every summer and spoke there during his several presidential campaigns. After his death in 1968, the colony's social hall was named for him.
The Society's land is held in common, but individual families own the residences they occupy, and a few units are available for rental. By 1947 the colony, sometimes known as Camp Three Arrows, consisted of fifty-three bungalows. The seventy-fifth, and final, unit was purchased in 1973. In the first few years residents dined communally, but later individual cabins had their own kitchens. Residences have been renovated and expanded to varying degrees and in different styles, with a number of families winterizing their properties for year-round use. Important community decisions at Three Arrows are made through a process of direct democracy. Management is in the hands of a Board of Directors, and a multitude of committees addresses specific areas of responsibility. Paid staff are the full-time caretaker and professional lifeguards, but community members often join in on maintenance projects. By the 1990s the community had become Putnam Valley's largest tax-payer. In the face of soaring land values and the tendency of children and grandchildren of society members to move away from New York and give up ownership of family properties, the community works hard to screen prospective buyers and maintain the cooperative values that motivated the founders.
The colony offers a lively schedule of summer cultural activity, including art classes, Friday-night lectures on political and social welfare topics, discussion sessions known as "schmoozes," concerts, amateur theatricals and dances. There are two clay tennis courts, a ball field and a marked trail for hiking. The community hosts a gala Fourth of July picnic, to which many non-residents are invited, and there is an annual Labor Day show. A waterfront swimming and boating area on fifty-acre Barger Pond, includes enclosed swimming "cribs" and a floating deck for lounging and socializing, and a number of supervised activities for children have been developed over the years.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Scope and Contents
This partially processed collection contains minutes and associated materials for meetings of the Board of Directors, Finance Committee, Membership Committee, and several other committees. The collection also includes general files that document the Society's history and operations, including background material on the colony's history, such as anniversary journals, charters, by-laws, files on sales of property and other land transactions, insurance records, and other legal records. Among the financial records are officers' reports, statements and expense and income ledgers. Committee activity is well documented: brochures, flyers and over three hundred and fifty photographs illustrate a wide range of community events and pastimes. A complete run of the Three Arrows newsletter, "Voice of the Hill," 1945-2013, and examples of other, more short-lived, publications are also included. The collection contains eleven oversize maps and plans of the Three Arrows property and Putnam Valley.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Cooperative societies -- New York (State).; Financial records; Photographs.; Correspondence.; Printed ephemera.; Socialism -- New York (State).; Putnam Valley (N.Y.).; Newsletters.; Minutes (administrative records); Legal documents.; blueprints (reprographic copies); Reports.; Glass, Joseph; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Barger Street Cooperative Society; Hay, Louis; Schaffer, Jack; Three Arrows Cooperative Society, Inc.; Balgley, Halona W.; Heinrich, Amy Vladeck
- Series I: Minutes, 1937-2002; 11639
  - Board of Directors/Executive Board, 1937-1938; 11680 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1939-1941; 11679 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors/Executive Board, 1942-1944; 11678 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, 1945-1946; 11677 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1947-1948; 11676 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1949-1950; 11675 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1953-1954; 11674 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors/Executive Board, 1955-1958; 11673 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, 1961-1963; 11672 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, 1964-1965; 11671 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, 1966-1968; 11670 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, 1969-1970; 11669 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, 1971; 11668 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, 1972-1973; 11667 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, 1974-1975; 11666 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1976-1977; 11665 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, 1978-1980; 11664 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors, 1981-1983; 11663 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, 1984-1985; 11662 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Board of Directors, 1986-1989; 11661 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Board of Directors, 1990-1993; 11660 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors, 1994-2002; 11659 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Finance Committee, 1937-1939, 1953, 1971; 11658 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Finance Committee, 1982-1989; 11657 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Insurance Committee, 1974-1978, 1982-1991; 11656 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, undated, 1964-1989; 11655 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1991-1997; 11654 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Membership Committee, 1940-1944; 11653 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Membership Committee, 1945-1948; 11652 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Membership Committee, 1949-1950; 11651 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Membership Committee, 1953-1958; 11650 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Membership Committee, 1961-1970; 11649 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Membership Committee, 1971-1973; 11648 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Membership Committee, 1974-1975; 11647 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Membership Committee, 1976-1980; 11646 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Membership Committee, 1981-1983; 11645 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Membership Committee, 1984-1989; 11644 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Membership Committee, 1990-1993; 11643 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Membership Committee, 1996, 1998, 2002; 11642 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Permanent Planning Committee, 1966-1977; 11641 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Water Committee, 1966, 1996; 11640 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series II: General Files, 1937-2003; 11459
  - Action Committee for Peace and Freedom: Proposal, undated; 11638 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Administration: General, 1997-1999; 11637 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Advertising, 1994; 11636 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Affiliations, 1938-1988; 11635 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anniversaries: General, undated, 1963, 1986-1996; 11634 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Anniversaries: Journals, 1976-1996; 11633 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Announcements, undated, 1993, 2000; 11632 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Application for a Permit to Maintain a Camp, 1940; 11631 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Appraisals: General, 1996, 1998-2000; 11630 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Appraisals: Residential Plans, 1998-2000; 11629 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Crafts Shows, 1971-1982; 11628 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Assessments: Complaints, 1976-1983, 1992-1998; 11627 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Assessments: General, undated, 1940-1969; 11626 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Assessments: General, 1970-1979; 11625 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Assessments: General, 1980-1998; 11624 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Barn, 1992-1994; 11623 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, 1939-1949, 1964-2002; 11622 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bosworth, Fred, 1962, 1971; 11621 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - By-Laws, undated, 1939-1957; 11620 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - By-Laws, 1962-1963, 1974-2001; 11619 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Capital Improvements, 1938-1950, 1985-1997; 11618 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Caretaker: Feirman, Jeffrey, 2000; 11617 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Caretaker: Garvin, Paul, 1991, 1998-1999; 11616 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Caretaker: General, undated, 1972-1973, 1978-2002; 11615 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Caretaker: Van Tassel, Robert, 1984-1988; 11614 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Certificates of Incorporation and Amendments, 1937, 1949-1953, 1961-1982; 11613 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Committees, undated, 1994-2002; 11612 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Community Land Tax, 1970-1981; 11611 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Commutation Questionnaire, undated; 11610 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Co-op Store, 1940-1965; 11609 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Undated; 1937-1939; 11608 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1951; 1959-1995; 11607 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Crib Construction, 1938; 11606 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Crossword Puzzle, undated; 11605 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Day Camp, 1943-1976; 1979; 1997-2002; 11604 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Deeds, 1937, 1953, 1998; 11603 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Department of Agriculture (New York State), 1964-1991; 11602 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Donations to Other Organizations, 1938-1996; 11601 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Dues: Correspondence, 1938, 1942-1949, 1963-2000; 11600 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Education Committee, 1938, 1944-1978, 1993-2001; 11599 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Election Fraud Case, undated; 11598 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Employees: Records, 1939-1941, 1962-1993; 11597 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Employees: Wages and Regulations, undated, 1941, 1960; 11596 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - End of the Season Check-list, undated; 11595 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Environmental Issues (at Three Arrows), 1984; 11594 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Events: General, undated; 1951; 1955-2002; 11593 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Finances: Check Stubs, 1944-1945; 11592 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Finances: General, 1937-1970; 11591 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Finances: General, 1972-1985; 11590 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Finances: General, 1986-1989; 11589 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Finances: General, 1990-2002; 11588 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1937-1941; 11587 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1941-1942; 11586 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1944-1945; 11585 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1946-1948; 11584 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1956-1962; 11583 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1965-1966; 11582 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1976-1977; 11581 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Finances: Ledger, 1977-1978; 11580 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Finances: Statements, 1937-1949; 11579 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Finances: Statements, 1950-1959; 11578 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Finances: Statements, 1960-1969; 11577 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Finances: Statements, 1970-1979; 11576 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Finances: Statements, 1980-1989; 11575 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fire Committee, 1955-1957, 1962; 11574 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Fischer, Bruno: "Notes for a Master's Thesis on a Summer Housing Cooperative Called Three Arrows", 1967; 11573 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - General Description, undated, 1984, 1996; 11572 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Governance: General, 2001; 11571 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Greenberg Case, 1947, 1964-1967; 11570 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Guest Request Form, 1946; 11569 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Health and Safety: Reports, etc., undated, 1943-1947, 1961-1979; 11568 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Health and Safety: Reports, etc., 1980-2002; 11567 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - History, undated, 1984, 1992-1995; 11566 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hotel License, 1957, 1960; 11565 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - House Renumbering, 1987; 11564 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Insurance, 1942-1959; 11563 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Insurance, 1960-1979; 11562 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Insurance, 1986-1989; 11561 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Insurance, 1990-2002; 11560 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Israel-Palestine, undated; 11559 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Labor Day Shows, 1950; 1962-1976; 1999-2002; 11558 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Labor Day Shows: Plays, undated, 1947-2000; 11557 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Labor Day Shows: Sheet Music, undated; 11556 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Labor Day Shows: Song Lyrics, undated, 1961-1964, 1976; 11555 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lake Committee, undated, 1957, 1977-2002; 11554 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Land Purchase, 1980-1981; 11553 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Landscaping/Beautification Committees, 1948, 1962-2000; 11552 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legal Committee, 1979-1980, 1997, 2001-2002; 11551 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Long Range Planning, 1992, 1996, 2002; 11550 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Management Committee, undated, 1943-1986, 2001-2002; 11549 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Maps and Plans, undated, 1941-1999; 11548 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Members: Complaints, 1938-1969, 1991, 2000; 11547 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Members: General, 1938; 1949; 1958; 1965; 1973; 11546 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Members: General, 1980-2001; 11545 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Membership Committee, 1937-1949; 11544 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Membership Committee, 1950-1969; 11543 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Membership Committee, 1970-1979; 11542 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Membership Committee, 1980-1990; 11541 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Membership Committee, 1991-1999, 2001; 11540 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Membership Lists, undated, 1937, 1953-1997; 11539 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Membership Policy, undated, 1939-2001; 11538 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mortgage Bonds, 1942; 11537 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Mortgage Consolidation, 1943; 11536 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Newsletter: "Echo of the Hills" (Youth Group), undated, 1984; 11535 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newsletter: General, undated; 11534 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter: "The Kid's Voice of the Hill", undated; 11533 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Camp", undated; 11532 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1945-1949; 11531 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1950-1959; 11530 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1960-1969; 11529 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1970-1975; 11528 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1976-1979; 11527 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1980-1983; 11526 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1984-1986; 11525 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1987-1989; 11524 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1990-1994; 11523 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1995-1997; 11522 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 1998-1999; 11521 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 2000-2001; 11520 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Newsletter: "The Voice of the Hill", 2002-2003; 11519 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Newsletter: "What's Cookin'", 1943; 11518 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - New York City Water Tunnels, undated; 11517 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Obituaries/Memorials, undated, 1970, 1995; 11516 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Officer Lists, 1938-1994; 11515 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Organization Committee, 1939; 11514 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pamphlet: "A Different Kind of Life", 1992; 11513 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Payroll Record, 1977-1987; 11512 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pension Plan, 1969-1987; 11511 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Planning and Building Committee: General, 1939-1994; 11510 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Planning and Building Committee: Surveys, 1994; 11509 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Playground and Nursery, [1940s?]; 11508 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Political Action Committee, undated; 11507 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - President's Annual Reports, 1943, 1946-1947, 1954-1980; 11506 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Property Description Reports, 1995; 11505 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Property Transactions: General, 1937-1978, 1995, 2002; 11504 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Property Leases, undated, 1979-2001; 11503 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Publicity, undated, 1937-1956; 11502 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Publicity, 1984-1996; 11501 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Putnam Valley, NY: History, 1966, 1986-1997; 11500 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Putnam Valley, NY: Planning, Zoning, Land Transfers, etc., undated, 1935-1957; 11499 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Putnam Valley, NY: Planning, Zoning, Land Transfers, etc., 1962-1996; 11498 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Racial Discrimination, 1943; 11497 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Receipt Book, 1943-1944; 11496 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Receipt Book, 1946-1948; 11495 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Recipe Book, undated; 11494 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Rentals: General, 1962-1997; 11493 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Rentals: Winter, 1983-1986; 11492 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Roads Committee, 1946-1994; 11491 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Rothberg, Diana: Proposed Dissertation on Three Arrows, 1972; 11490 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sale of Property, undated, 1947, 1956-1958; 11489 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Sale of Property, 1965, 1966, 1974-1987; 11488 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sale of Property, 1989-1996; 11487 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Security and Emergency Policy, 2000; 11486 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Shareholder Transactions, 1939, 1957, 1963-1979; 11485 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Shareholder Transactions, 1983-1998; 11484 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Snow Plow Policy, 2000; 11483 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Social Committee, 1945-1969; 11482 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Social Committee, 1970-2000; 11481 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Social Hall, 1953-1954, 1971, 1993-1997; 11480 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Speakers, 1966; 11479 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Sports Committee, 1943-1980, 1996; 11478 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Swimming Pool Proposal, 1981; 11477 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Taxes, 1939-1979; 11476 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Taxes, 1980-1984; 11475 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Taxes, 1985-1989; 11474 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Taxes, 1995-2000; 11473 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Tennis Courts, 1968, 1996; 11472 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Thomas, Norman, 1966; 11471 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Trusts: Discussion of, 1987-1996; 11470 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Waiver Committee, 1997-1998; 11469 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Washer and Dryer, 1965-1966; 11468 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Waste Disposal, 1990; 11467 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Water Committee, 1938-1969; 11466 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Water Committee, 1970-1997; 11465 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Waterfront: Regulations, etc., 1947-2001; 11464 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Wetlands, 1976; 11463 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Workshops, undated, 1975-2001; 11462 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Wyle, Benjamin, 1984; 11461 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Finances: Two Oversize Ledgers, 1938-1950, 1959-1960; 11460 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series III: Unprocessed Materials, 1930's-2000's; 299723
  - Minutes, Newsletters, Flyers and Notices, 1940's-1960's; 299788 (Box 8)
  - Newsletters, Journals, Maps, Membership Funds and Founding Documents, 1930's-1940's; 1960's-2000's; 299789 (Box 9)